do meditation and we'll go through the
back up after the three-day retreat I'll
read you the scripture you can fall
asleep
the
check your phone
[Music]
blow your nose
anybody want share you could play horn
on our next coin
[Music]
okay then get saddled closer eyes don't
get jet lag
I mean action now little smile relax
your eyes give up all the stuff you're
thinking about you can you can do it
later it will wait for you relax your
shoulders relax your fingers try to just
enjoy and give up all your worries all
your plans you can take care of them
later they never stop
you will die before they stop
take a Dharma break
check in with your teacher go to the
middle of your heart go deep they'll
like you guide into a pool and you're
underwater and you're going down down
down into your heart and you meet your
blue is your teacher down there inside a
grain of sugar you it gets just big
enough to fit both of you in a grain of
sugar sit with them there and quiet
you're inside your heart sit with them
inside a grain of sugar clear
take a moment to settle down and connect
with your teacher
now I'd like to think a skew to think of
one of the most frightening times of
your life Hector told me a story about
he was in retreat recently far away from
other people and he was bitten by
scorpion and he thought it might be the
kind that kills you and so he he had a
strange experience where he had like a
half hour or an hour and he thought it's
very possible he will die within that
that's are still far away for other
people to help him and just think of
something like that some situations in
your life which was hopeless and
dangerous myself I remember I was on a
plane and they told us the the landing
gear was not working and we might die
and so I think of a most terrible moment
in your life most sad moment most
dangerous moments the moment when you
were most having despair and you you
thought everything was impossible
try to remember a moment like that
then the long rim instruction for those
moments usually you're too scared to
think deeply about emptiness or there's
no time the plane is falling you have a
few minutes left
after the scorpion value and it's very
difficult to think clearly about
emptiness or trying to go through the
death process or something like that so
the Longmen service in those moments
just say the name of your refuge it's
okay
se llama llama llama okay
say your Namas name say Buddha just say
your teacher's name if you can you can
do a mantra llamas name mantra you can
say ohm and then if the llamas name is
John Brady didn't say um John Brady
awful because you're too scared to think
of anything else you can say the whole
mantra ultimate refuge mantras own John
Brady ah whoo
I'm falling down my airplanes falling
down um don't burn your home John video
hope it means help me John Brady it's
not your route teacher okay or you can
use your own teacher's name okay so um
see your teacher's name awesome okay if
the plane is really falling down you
probably won't be able to remember the
mantra
so the lamrim says just say your llamas
name John John John John okay so in this
meditation you just
practice calling your mama's name when
you're in very serious danger and you
too terrified or you're too sad to
remember anything else or think about
anything else just say their name John
John turn then you hit the ground okay
with your llamas name on your lips
so practice in your mind now remember
some situations like that
and visualize yourself just repeating
your mama's myths as you die or as
something terrible happens to you
we'll stay here for a few minutes
and please come back to your breath
sweet deep exhales check with your mama
in your heart and then bring your mind
back to this room you can open your eyes
take your stretch
what's the meditation call
[Music]
in moments of fear and pain okay in
moments of fear and pain number 14
okay yeah yeah and then it says even
just the words okay so this lineage
Diamond Mountain lineage okay our
lineage nuttin when you call that neo
song copying then it's okay we are neo
total copies we're very big on the
meaning of things and we don't we're
trying not to do meaningless rituals you
know go to the temple wave incense and
you're going to go to tushy to heaven
you know we're trying not to encourage
people to do things that they don't
understand or that are not going to help
them very much but there are exceptions
okay if you really believe in your Reed
Lama if you really have a proper
relationship with your heart teacher
whether it's a living person whether
it's a Buddha who lived a thousand years
ago whether if someone you haven't met
yet but you can imagine them okay either
one the power of your heart teacher is
so big that if you just say their names
when you're having extreme troubles like
about to hit the ground in airplane or
about to die from a scorpion sting it's
okay it works okay because of the power
of the your lama name is more powerful
than buddha okay so it's okay in this
meditation you're going to practice
getting hit by a car
or practice your airplane falling down
or practice I don't know you know
someone cheats a gun I had that happen
to me once this guy was following me too
close and I put my brakes on in there
then he got angry and he followed me and
I finally I turned the corner and I
stopped and he came up next to me and he
shot a gun at me and I felt the powder
hit my face in them it went through the
windows you know and it missed me you
know then it's something like that
happens here you know just something
happens and you get shot then llamas
name died okay that's the best you can
do and it's and it's good it's
sufficient got it so let's practice
during the three days okay what I'm
going to do is someone like if they if
they just come up to me and shoot me in
the head then you should have something
ready right it happens
weird stuff happens do you remember Tom
Kiley no he's brought Daniel his brother
someone in the East Village came up to
him and punch him in the face as hard as
he could just walking down just
sudden favor and he just fell in the
ground he's bleeding and he's like well
you know then you could say then so
medication number 14 is emergency box
you know push the button along with me
that's all okay Mama's name